Inventory of the Julia Tung collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Julia Tung collection
1959-2006
1989
90100
Hoover Institution Archives
8 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 3 oversize folders, 4 digital files (8.2 linear feet, .0009 GB)
Press releases, letters, pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, writings, election campaign literature, photographs, slides, sound recordings, video tapes, microfilm, and banners relating to the Tiananmen Square incident in China in 1989, to protests of the incident held by Chinese student dissidents in the United States, and to elections in Taiwan.
Tung, Julia, collector.
Access
Boxes 11-12 closed until 2020 March 1. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Press releases, letters, pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, writings, election campaign literature, photographs, slides, sound recordings, video tapes, microfilm, and banners, relating to the Tiananmen Square incident in China in 1989, to protests of the incident held by Chinese student dissidents in the United States, and to elections in Taiwan.
Original file names have been maintained where present and are indicated by quotation marks around the title.
China--History--Tiananmen Square Incident, 1989.; Chinese students--United States.; Dissenters--China.; Elections--Taiwan.; Slides (Photography).; Video tapes.; Audiotapes.
- North America Chinese language broadcast, "I Am Chai Ling - I Am Alive!" 北美華語廣播網之, "我是柴琳 - 我還活著!,", undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note 范围和内容
  See also: Box 9. 参见第9箱。
- Day of Grief 國哀, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  General note
  Contains printed matter.
- "Newspaper (copy) and T.V. clip [about Tiananmen Square incident]" 關於天安門事件的報紙複印件和電視稿, undated (Box-folder 1: 3)
- "A Word of Advice to the Politburo" by He Xin 何新撰寫《對政治局的忠告》, undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
- "Collection of Students’ Flyers in the Tiananmen Incident (May 1989)" by Haiqing Wu "天安門廣場事件之學生傳單集,", 1995 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- The Australian National University 澳大利亞國立大學, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  Empty folder 空信封。
- Tiananmen Square influence in France and the United States 天安門事件在法國和美國的影響, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  Includes materials featuring student leaders' declaration of Democratic China in Paris and materials documenting the influence of the Tiananmen Square Incident in Mountain View and San Jose, California communities. 含民主中国宣言(巴黎), 以及学潮在加州山景市和圣何塞市的影响。
- Organizations supporting June 4th movement 支持中國六四運動的社會組織, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Printed matter on Beijing riot 印刷讀物－北京風波, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  "The June Turbulence in Beijing," "Fourth Plenary Session of the CPC 13th Central Committee," "How Chinese View the Riot in Beijing," "Report on Putting Down Anti-Government Riot" by New Star Publisher. Includes a Christmas card to Julia Tung. 含关于天安门事件的英文读物和(收件)圣诞贺卡。
- The First Congress of the Chinese students in the U.S. 第一屆全美中國學生學者代表大會, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- From the Vantage of the Beijing Hotel: Peeping Into the 1989 Student Unrest in China by James C. Hsing 紐約大學James C Hsing之學潮紀實論文 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Consulate General of the People’s Republic of China press release 中國駐舊金山總領事館新聞發布會, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 12)
- Chinese Democratic Movement leaders in San Francisco 學潮領袖在舊金山, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 13)
- Tiananmen Is Weeping published by Taipei Guanguang Association 《天安門在哭泣》出版於台北市觀光協會, undated (Box-folder 1: 14)
- Description of photos owned by Union of Patriotic Democracy movement of Hong Kong citizens and samples 香港公民收集中國民主運動中心照片說明, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
  Contains a timeline of march, hunger strikes, Tiananmen Square incident, and post-incident activities. 含1989年4月19日至1989年6月30日游行，绝食，天安门事变及后期活动的时间线。
- Liu Shanqing 劉山青文件, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Photographs from Dr. Harmon C. Thomas 來自Harmon C Thomas博士的相片, 1993 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Letters received from Wang Guanquan 來自王觀泉的信件, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  Contains photographs of Tiananmen Square incident. 含天安门事件相片。
- Operational plan for the Tiananmen Square protest 天安門遊行的計劃說明, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  Contains declaration, manual, open letters, and more. 内含宣言，说明，公开信，等。
- "Military general’s response to division of central commander of Beijing (seven leaders)" 軍方七位高級將領表態, undated (Box-folder 2: 6)
- "General Secretary Jiang Zemin on China’s policy on Chinese students abroad by PRC Consulate General, S. F. 6/18/90" 江澤民在中國駐舊金山總領事館關於中國對中國海外學生政策的發布會, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Organizations of pro-democracy movement of China ‘89 information survey form 各地支持八九中國民運團體資料調查表, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- "Gary Gach collection of Tiananmen eye witness records" 由Gary Gach收藏的目擊者記錄, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Dong Wenzhu 董文鑄檔案, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  Materials on Dong Wenzhu’s identity as a former landlord. 主要内容围绕董文铸的地主身份。
- Memorial flyer 追悼會傳單, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 11)
- The Federation for a Democratic China, USA branch meeting minutes "民主中国阵线美国分部成立大会纪要", 1990 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- "Organizations: and their public programs 1990" 組織：公共節目1990 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  Includes musical program and concert flyer using Tiananmen Square Incident as theme. 包含以天安门事件为主题的音乐剧节目单和演唱会传单。
- "Tiananmen Square Incident, 6/4/89, name list of captives and fugitives" 被捕民運人士，及通緝名單, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 14)
- "'Xu Jiatun, gone to U.S.' by David Chen, South China Morning Post, 5/12/90" 前香港新華社社長，許家屯, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 15)
- Personalities from the Democracy Movements in China: Brief Biography 人物傳記：中國民主運動的性格, undated (Box-folder 2: 16)
  Includes biographies of Democratic movement student leaders. 包含学潮领袖的人物传记。
- "The Federation for a Democratic China, U. S. Silicon Valley - Newsletter" 美國矽谷民主中國聯合會 - 通訊, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 2: 17)
- "The Federation for a Democratic China - Newsletters, and brief introduction no. 1-11" (Paris) 民主中國陣線會員通訊(巴黎), 1989-1990 (Box-folder 2: 18)
- Goddess of Democracy postcard 民主女神明信片, undated (Box-folder 2: 19)
- "Republic of China - election, president" 中華民國 - 競選,總統, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Pillar of Shame 國殤之柱, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- The 51st Club 五一俱樂部 / 正清社, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- "Korean President in Stanford 6/12/98 - Demonstrations material donated by Julia Tung" 韓國總統1998年6月12日訪斯坦福 - Julia Tung收藏戰時資料 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Tiananmen June the Fourth Hundredth Day Memorial poster, 天安門六四百日紀念, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Tiananmen incident clippings and articles 天安門事件報紙摘要和文章, 1989-1996 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Tiananmen June the Fourth 10th year anniversary clippings 天安門六四事件10週年報導等, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- NYPL Tiananmen Archive (microfilm) NYPL 天安門檔案 (微縮電影版), 1990 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- News from Asia Watch 人權觀察, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Photographs from Jia Guorong 賈國榮相片 (來信), 2001 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  Includes a 3.5 inch floppy disk. 含3.5寸相片磁盘。
- Taipei Neihu Technology Park brochure 台北內湖科技園區宣傳冊, undated (Box-folder 4: 3)
- Falun Dafa (Falun Gong) 法輪大法 (法輪功), 2001 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- The Federation for a Democratic China booklets 民主中國陣線冊子, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  Contains both photocopies and original printed matter. 包含相片和原始印刷资料。
- The Federation for a Democratic China booklets and clippings 民主中國陣線冊子和报纸, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  Contains newspaper and magazines. 包含报纸和杂志。
- The Federation for a Democratic China documents 民主中國陣線文件, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  Includes lecture flyers, fundraiser dinner invitation, articles, and newsletter. 包括讲座传单，募捐晚会邀请函，文章，报纸通讯。
- "[1989] Beijing Massacre, List of Known Victims" 北京大屠殺遇難者名單, 2000 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- "Six Plenary Session summary" (classified file 1 of 3) 六中全會傳達提綱（1）, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 9)
- "Witness 6.3" (classified file 2 of 3) 目擊6.3（2）, undated (Box-folder 4: 10)
- "June 4th movement, 1989 - on site photos + notes of happenings, witness" (classified file 3 of 3), 六四事件, 一九八九年 - 現場相片，記錄筆記，目擊（3） (Box-folder 4: 11)
  Includes photographs and a photocopy of Julia Tung's folder for Hua Guofeng's top secret file (no content). 包含相片和Julia Tung收藏之华国锋密档信封的复印件。
- Xu Jiatun articles and photographs 許家屯文章和照片, 1990-2001 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  Includes photographs of Xu Jiatun in Los Angeles. 包括许家屯在洛杉矶相片。
- "Chinese Tiananmen Square Movement 6/4/89" 天安門廣場運動, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  Contains Julia Tung's handwritten notes. 含Julia Tung书写笔记。
- The Chronicle of the Federation for a Democratic China 《民陣一年》, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 4: 14)
- Falun Gong / Dafa books and catalog records 法輪功 / 大法印刷冊, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- "Photos of Chiang Ching-kuo family" 蔣經國家庭生活相片, 1945-1980s, circa 2006 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  Contains printed photo files, not actual photographs.
- Falun Gong / Dafa clippings and manual 法轮功 / 大法报纸和注解, 1999-2005 (Box-folder 5: 3)
- Falun Gong / Dafa publicity material 法輪功 / 大法宣傳資料，, 2003 (Box-folder 5: 4)
- Writings and meeting transcript 寫作和會議講話, 1981-2004 (Box-folder 5: 5)
- Yin Haiguang 殷海光, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  See also: Box 10. 交叉参考第10箱。
- The SOAR Foundation 樹華教育基金會, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 5: 7)
- Photographs 相片, 1989
  Contains photos related to the Tiananmen Square Incident in Beijing and protest in San Francisco. Negatives are closed. 含天安门事件和后期旧金山抗议相片。底片不开放。
  - "Mr. David Tawei Lee 李大维先生,", undated (Box 6)
  - "Mr. Vincent C. Siew 蕭萬長先生,", undated
  - "Mr. Lee Teng-Hui 李登辉先生,", undated
  - "Mr. Lien Chan 連戰先生,", undated
  - Taiwan bank 台灣銀行, undated
  - Taiwan notebook computers 應用電腦展
  - The IDF fighter, IDF 戰機, undated
  - Taiwan air transshipment 台湾空運, undated
  - "The Taiwan skyline 台北市容,", undated
  - Hsinchu Science-based Industrial Park 新竹工業園區, undated
  - "T'ien-an men Incident in Beijing, June 1989 - Chinese in U.S. demonstrating in S.F., California, June 4, 1989 天安門事件 - 中美加州舊金山示範,"
  - "6 Chinese Dissidents in Hilton Hotel, S.F., Wa'er Kaisi 六位持不同政见者舊金山 Hilton Hotel集合, 吾爾開希,", 1989 August 8
  - Tiananmen Square Protests in Beijing 天安門事件, 1989 May 4 - June 18
  - "Demonstration in S.F., Ca. 加州舊金山示範,", 1989 August 8
  - Panel discussion post-Tiananmen Square protest 天安門事件候討論會, 1989
  - Unidentified photos 未确认的照片, 1989 May 7
  - Student protest leader speech 學生抗議隊長言講, 1989
  - Beijing riots photo negatives 北京天安門事件底片, 1989 May-June
  - Tiananmen Square protests in Beijing slides 北京天安門事件变幻灯片, 1989 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Calligraphy 書法, undated
  Access
  Originals are closed and may not be used without permission of the Archivist. Use copies can be found in Box 5, Folder 8.
  Includes 1 poster, 2 single banners, and 11 pairs of couplets. 含海报１张，挽联２幅，对联11对。
  - Poster and single banners 海報和獨體輓聯
    - Poster 海報 (Oversize folder 1)
    - 向天安門偉大烈士致敬 - 北加州台大校友會
    - 向天安門偉大烈士致哀 - 北加州台大校友會
  - Couplet pair 1 第一組對聯
    - 地狱鬼重现北京城
    - 天安門變成屠宰場
  - Couplet pair 2 第二組對聯
    - 拋頭顱灑熱血中國學生創造了新歷史
    - 爭自由求民主中國學生喚起了民族魂
  - Couplet pair 3 第三組對聯
    - 哭我愛國青年慘被屠殺
    - 哀我中華民族痛失菁英
  - Couplet pair 4 第四組對聯
    - 寧高鳴而就死不緘默而苟生年少以天下為己任 (Oversize folder 2)
    - 奮赤手當坦克用血肉對機槍浩氣歷千秋尚凜然 - 鄭洪，崔志潔
  - Couplet pair 5 第五組對聯
    - 法古今完人
    - 養天地正氣
  - Couplet pair 6 第六組對聯
    - 一夜血染天安門
    - 萬民痛恨共產黨
  - Couplet pair 7 第七組對聯
    - 上天要共產黨緘亡
    - 先要使共產黨瘋狂
  - Couplet pair 8 第八組對聯
    - 舉世奮怨赤色暴政
    - 全民傷痛愛國学生
  - Couplet pair 9 第九組對聯
    - 紫禁城內有心人士揮指鄧李師 - 北加州臺大校友會全體敬挽 (Oversize folder 3)
    - 天安門外無限学子高呼自由化 - 天安門事变大陸学生死難千古
  - Couplet pair 10 第十組對聯
    - 辨忠奸左醉右躬至今有小人 - 北加州台大校友會敬挽
    - 擁黨政前仆後繼自古美君子 - 天安門事变大陸殉難学生千古
  - Couplet pair 11 第十一組對聯
    - 学生愛國無罪竟遭人民軍殺戮
    - 天安門前血債誓要共產黨血償
  - Calligraphy use copies 書法用副, undated (Box-folder 5: 8)
- Videorecordings 視頻錄製, 1989-1994, undated
  - VHS videotape cassettes 錄像帶 VHS, 1989-1994
    Videos organized in original orders and perserved with original titles. Videos featuring materials related to Tiananmen Square Incident. 录像带按原顺序和原名收藏。包含天安门事件资料。
    - The People’s dictator, 90 yr old (Teng Xiao-ping), BBC London, 1994 (Box 7)
      See also: Box 1. 见第一箱。
    - Mao -- last emperor, Interview Li Chih-shui Mao's doctor, BBC London, undated
    - T'ian-an men incident in Beijing #1, abridged version CBS, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident in Beijing 1, CBS TV recording 1, 1989
    - T'ian men incident in Beijing #2, abridged version CBS, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident in Beijing #2, CBS recording, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident in Beijing #3. CBS T.V. recording, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident in Beijing, Part 4, CBS T. V. news, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident in Beijing, #5 Part I, CBS News Coverage, 1989
    - T'ien'an men incident in Beijing, #5 Part II, CBS News Coverage, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident in Beijing, #6, CBS News Coverage, 1989
    - T'ien'an men incident, Beijing, Tape 7 Part I, CBS News Coverage, 1989
    - T'ien'an men incident, Beijing, Tape 7 Part II, CBS News Coverage, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident, Beijing, #8, CBS News Coverage, 1989
    - T'ien'an men incident in Beijing, PRC Consular copy, Part 3, 1989
    - T'ien-an-men Democracy Movement Archive, video taped by Hongkong Broadcast, 星期一檔案（六四天安門）H.K. 有配音, 1989 (Box 8)
    - T'ian-an men incident in Beijing, World Journal Coverage, 1989
    - T'ian-an men incident in Beijing, Taipei News Roc Sponsored, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident in Beijing, PRC Reports Part I, 1989
    - T'ien-an men incident in Beijing, PRC Reports Part I, 1989
    - LEI MING YUAN, Le Tonnerre qui chante au loin, Vincent lebbe "L'aujourd' hui de Dieu,", 1990
  - DVD, undated
    - 中國長春, undated
  - Video CDs 視頻 CD, undated
    - "我們告訴未來”, undated
    - "The real stories of Falun Dafa,", undated
    - “鬱金香，昨天和今天的故事......”, undated
- Sound recordings 音頻錄音, 1989-1997, undated
  - Student protest song, 1989 (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 90100_a_0002857
  - 柴玲的聲音, 1989
  - China by Jean Baez, 1989
  - "All For Freedom" 為自由, undated
  - City arts and lectures, Iris Chang in conversation with Orville Schell, undated
  - 陳履安參選總統的心路之旅, undated
    See also: Box 3, Folder 1. 见第３箱第１文件夹。
  - 歷史的傷口, undated
  - BBC中文節目《文革30年系列》(1-20), undated
  - Audio CDs 音頻 CD, 1997, undated
    - Voice of the Giant - Mao Zedong 巨人之聲 - 毛澤東, 1997 (Box 10)
    - Voice of the Giant - Zhou Enlai 巨人之聲 - 周恩來, 1997
    - Voice of the Giant - Deng Xiaoping 巨人之聲 - 鄧小平, 1997
    - 台灣公共電視百年任務志，殷海光, undated
      See also: Box 5, Folder 6. 见第５箱第６文件夹。
- CLOSED (Boxes 11-12)